export const data = [
  {
    question: "Which gas is primarily responsible for trapping heat in the Earth's atmosphere?",
    option1: "Oxygen",
    option2: "Carbon Dioxide (CO2)",
    option3: "Nitrogen",
    option4: "Methane",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the main source of carbon dioxide emissions?",
    option1: "Transportation",
    option2: "Industrial processes",
    option3: "Deforestation",
    option4: "Burning fossil fuels",
    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the term used to describe the gradual increase in the Earth's average temperature?",
    option1: "Global cooling",
    option2: "Climate shift",
    option3: "Global warming",
    option4: "Temperature flux",
    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following activities contributes to deforestation?",
    option1: "Logging",
    option2: "Agriculture",
    option3: "Urbanization",
    option4: "All of the above",
    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the main greenhouse gas emitted from agricultural activities?",
    option1: "Carbon Dioxide (CO2)",
    option2: "Methane (CH4)",
    option3: "Nitrous Oxide (N2O)",
    option4: "Water Vapor (H2O)",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "Which sector is the largest contributor to global CO2 emissions?",
    option1: "Agriculture",
    option2: "Industry",
    option3: "Transportation",
    option4: "Residential and commercial buildings",
    ans: 3,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the main cause of the hole in the ozone layer?",
    option1: "Carbon emissions",
    option2: "CFCs (Chlorofluorocarbons)",
    option3: "Deforestation",
    option4: "Methane emissions",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is a predicted consequence of global warming?",
    option1: "Decrease in sea levels",
    option2: "Increase in extreme weather events",
    option3: "Expansion of polar ice caps",
    option4: "Decrease in average global temperature",
    ans: 2,
  },
  {
    question: "What is the term used to describe the process of Earth's temperature increasing due to greenhouse gases trapping heat?",
    option1: "Global warming",
    option2: "Climate change",
    option3: "Thermal expansion",
    option4: "Greenhouse effect",
    ans: 4,
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a renewable source of energy?",
    option1: "Solar",
    option2: "Wind",
    option3: "Coal",
    option4: "Hydroelectric",
    ans: 3,
  },
];
